[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339846", "question": "What TV family includes Gomez, Morticia, and Pugsley?", "answer": "Addams Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c114", "question": "What year was Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1ef80145fb2946670738d", "question": "What nut is hidden in Christmas rice pudding in Sweden?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e7", "question": "Everglades National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec244b8dc25ca9e12ef637", "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3f26ce05a3942286f29", "question": "Colin Hay is the founder and lead vocalist for what rock band?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec5", "question": "What novel begins with \"It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen\"?", "answer": "Nineteen Eighty-four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339396", "question": "Who directed the 1999 movie \"Bowfinger\"?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a077", "question": "In the TV series \"Leave It To Beaver\", what was Wally's best friend's name?", "answer": "Eddie Haskell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b268", "question": "What metal was found in Nevada's famed Comstock Lode?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339064", "question": "Which Latin word is used to express the meaning \"word for word\"?", "answer": "Verbatim", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdcb9e347d002c297e4ea", "question": "President Richard Nixon called what songstress an \"Ambassador of Love\"?", "answer": "Pearl Baily", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b398", "question": "Who founded the American Red Cross?", "answer": "Clara Barton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c807", "question": "What grapefruit-sized object has been reckoned to be the largest single cell on earth?", "answer": "An ostrich egg yolk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a355", "question": "What is the former name of Istanbul?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b591", "question": "What does the abbreviation MBA stand for in the MBA master's degree designation?", "answer": "Master of Business Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339294", "question": "The movie \"300\" is based on the graphic novel by which comic writer and artist?", "answer": "Frank Miller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02d", "question": "\u201cWhat hath God wrought\u201d was the first message ever sent on what type of a communication device?", "answer": "Telegraph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff511baff04d658268c92c9", "question": "What was the first major war campaign fought entirely by air forces?", "answer": "The\u00a0Battle of Britain -- The Royal Air Force defended the United Kingdom against attacks from the German Air Force (Luftwaffe).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03a", "question": "Who received the third most popular votes in the 1992 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Ross Perot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be25", "question": "In 2001, what surpassed tuna as America's most eaten seafood?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b00", "question": "What 1960's television series was set at the fictitious Coral Key Park & Marine Preserve?", "answer": "Flipper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d116b84fea7fe947a22272", "question": "Who wrote the 1938 play \"The Corn Is Green\"?", "answer": "Emlyn Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071fe43745b36be73039ed", "question": "What does an Advent calendar count down to?", "answer": "Christmas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f65", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95f", "question": "Which numbers are either side of the number sixteen on a dart board?", "answer": "7 and 8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a8b02404ad935a7e1a644", "question": "What is the BTS Variety Show called on their V-LIVE channel?", "answer": "Run BTS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c368", "question": "What acid gives citrus fruits their distinctive sharp flavor?", "answer": "Citric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338907", "question": "What Canadian Island was the setting for \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fec", "question": "Thomas Harris created what character?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b537", "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?", "answer": "Forty-two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049ca0cf93664eb10486a8", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6c", "question": "With which team did Brett Favre start his professional football career in 1991?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3d", "question": "What singer's autobiography was titled \"Man in Black\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339845", "question": "Julie Andrews won an Oscar for her role in what Disney classic?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3be", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's crust?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c519", "question": "What lemon-scented oil is derived from dried grasses and used as an insect repellent?", "answer": "Citronella", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f20", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Rosemary Murphy and Jennifer Jason Leigh?", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fa", "question": "What is the common name for the fruit Citrus grandis?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e806f6de59ea584496feb5", "question": "Which two South American countries do not share a land boundary with Brazil?", "answer": "Chile and Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d01152800b05cac20f0c", "question": "In what city was Bruce Lee born in?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb10", "question": "What is the nickname given to the stretch between San Jose and San Francisco known for its many technology businesses?", "answer": "Silicon Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45a", "question": "In which US state would you find Glacier National Park?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4eacd06d333868d34d75d", "question": "Who was the first democratically elected president of Russia?", "answer": "Boris Yeltsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd703e347d002c297e4be", "question": "Which pioneer of modern nursing had a cat called Bismark?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f15", "question": "What author created Lilliput?", "answer": "Jonathan Swift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8cc", "question": "What chain opened its first store in 1962 in the town of Rogers, Arkansas?", "answer": "Wal-Mart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597ddf6d77980686f722d185", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28b", "question": "Who is the lead singer of Metallica?", "answer": "James Hetfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab7", "question": "In the movie \"Home Alone\" what nickname did the burglars bestow upon themselves?", "answer": "The Wet Bandits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baaa", "question": "\"Double Your Pleasure, Double Your Fun\" was an ad slogan used by what product?", "answer": "Wrigley's Doublemint Gum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bf", "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392eb", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Thelma?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eb72fe83fe1f2a824bf8", "question": "The apostle Paul was called by Jesus on the road to which city?", "answer": "Damascus -- Paul was sent from Jerusalem to Damascus to arrest followers of Jesus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49e", "question": "Which European country is stereotypically associated with tulips, windmills and clogs?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede30d6ce05a3942286dd0", "question": "Who originally sang \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\"?", "answer": "Gene Autry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc2c", "question": "Which University did Bill Gates drop out of to start his own company?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339514", "question": "Who voiced Pinocchio in Disney's 1940 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dickie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338971", "question": "What sport was most frequently featured in Degas' paintings?", "answer": "Horseracing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea8360ff048f679a45ac27", "question": "What animal is known as \"the unicorn of the sea\"?", "answer": "Narwhal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339606", "question": "Who was the fugitive in the 1993 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dr. Richard Kimble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcda", "question": "What did Coleco name its 1983 home computer?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64f", "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the \"Queen City\"?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba7", "question": "Which one of tennis' Grand Slam tournaments is held in January?", "answer": "Australian Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f7d4cee580c7f8fd1e5f", "question": "What does the word \"Radar\" stand for?", "answer": "RAdio Detection And Ranging", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66284a5bfecdd737e0845", "question": "What was Mickey Mouse originally called?", "answer": "Mortimer Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c0962b316f4693fb6797", "question": "What app, a monster hit in 2016, has been credited with teaching Americans the metric system?", "answer": "Pok\u00e9mon GO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf5", "question": "What river is the setting for the novel \"The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991a", "question": "What was Billy Joel\u2019s first Top 40 hit?", "answer": "Piano Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb2c865ff7d326b622a79", "question": "What decade did film start to slowly replace glass in making photographic negatives?", "answer": "1880s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e7", "question": "What city is home to the University of Haiti?", "answer": "Port-au-Prince", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339186", "question": "Who was The Black Adder?", "answer": "Rowan Atkinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afcf", "question": "Which US president was nicknamed the \"Little Magician\"?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f7", "question": "Which is the largest state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd19", "question": "What vegetable is found in dishes served \"Florentine\" style?", "answer": "Spinach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad30", "question": "What US president endorsed the Louisiana Purchase in 1803?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fda", "question": "Pax was the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdd60740499cffc60b84238", "question": "Which European country was occupied by Britain from 1814 until 1964?", "answer": "Malta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049b64cf93664eb104869f", "question": "Which producer on the TV show \"Lost\" co-created the comic book series \"Y: The Last Man\"?", "answer": "Brian K. Vaughan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3893ff048f679a45ab25", "question": "What color catches the eye first?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db0", "question": "What is the name of the American musician best known as the lead singer of the rock band Nirvana?", "answer": "Kurt Cobain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef92cd6ce05a3942286e87", "question": "Which famous actor was orginally offered the role of Tommy Williams in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95f", "question": "What is the study of soil called?", "answer": "Pedology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff144a6b0ee8c595b6d39b6", "question": "What is the name of the first \"Sherlock Holmes\" novel?", "answer": "\"A Study in Scarlet\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be70", "question": "What is Michigan Stadium also known as?", "answer": "The Big House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5941257abab1e6f9796f1b54", "question": "Which character is always trying to steal the secret Krusty Krab Recipe on \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Plankton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c77", "question": "What year was Indiana Jones first introduced to the public?", "answer": "1981", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb50", "question": "What does the abbreviation ROI stand for in the financial world?", "answer": "Return on Investment", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ff", "question": "Lucille Fay LeSueur became famous as who?", "answer": "Joan Crawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a987761d1b4d384d5d68c", "question": "Which TV network ran the TV show \"Bonanza\" from 1959 to 1973?", "answer": "NBC", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda6a6ce05a3942286d85", "question": "What is Mr. Bean's actual first name?", "answer": "According to his television shows and movies, Mr. Bean's first name is actually \"Mr.\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b472e662d71a53650fea", "question": "Where is Michelangelo's \"David\" located?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b004", "question": "What city hosted the 1984 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a0", "question": "Which country hosted the 1924 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2e", "question": "Who wrote \"Il Milione\" while in prison?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd96e1c23c87fd04dd15e33", "question": "What sport was Abraham Lincoln a champion in?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c0", "question": "What year was Indira Gandhi assassinated?", "answer": "1984", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c210", "question": "When were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1924", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3d", "question": "What did the Texan army shout during the Battle of San Jacinto?", "answer": "Remember the Alamo!", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fa", "question": "What metal do you get from Hematite?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01d", "question": "What popular sport did James Naismith invent?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3c", "question": "Who played Stifler's mom in the American Pie movies?", "answer": "Jennifer Coolidge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595643fe803c1f1ebcc4a032", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a820", "question": "What river forms much of the border between Washington and Oregon?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c862", "question": "What's the common name for the foot ailment also called verrucas?", "answer": "Plantar warts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65e5b1f3c0ead6880d62a", "question": "In the 12th chapter of the \"Book of Revelation\", which angel leads a battle against a dragon?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ef", "question": "How does a beaver signal to other beavers that danger is present?", "answer": "Slaps its tail on the water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62e", "question": "To which color group does St. Charles Place belong on a standard US Monopoly board?", "answer": "Light purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea353bff048f679a45aaff", "question": "Which planet is known as the Evening Star?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012152463c99d48cd169ae7", "question": "What did Einstein reportedly do to stay focused?", "answer": "Play music -- His wife Elsa said that when he was struggling with a theory he would play a few chords on the piano to focus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6692552a821ff76ae8b09", "question": "Who was Abraham's second wife?", "answer": "According to Genesis 2:15, Abraham's second wife was Keturah.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e1d6fe83fe1f2a824b99", "question": "What was the \"The Blitz\"?", "answer": "A term used for Germany\u2019s bombing campaign on London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339634", "question": "What was Doogie Howser's real first name?", "answer": "Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592ead58f83302ff91e4647a", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68c", "question": "What river flows along the western boundary of New Jersey?", "answer": "Delaware River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c031", "question": "What is the fear of fire known as?", "answer": "Pyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2148831a458464a93c458", "question": "A sentence, verse, etc., that includes all the letters of the alphabet is called what?", "answer": "Pangram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbaed190738315b1fb74e2e", "question": "In what year did the first president of Kenya die?", "answer": "1978", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac2", "question": "What do the letters YMCA stand for?", "answer": "Young Men\u2019s Christian Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5b", "question": "What year did the Bhopal disaster occur?", "answer": "1984", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f166fbf7c52aae91cc07b4", "question": "Which is the largest of Neptune's moons?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbdc36ce05a3942286ee1", "question": "What was the name of the bar Jerry Lundegaard went to in the film \"Fargo\"?", "answer": "King of Clubs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a727", "question": "Which six states share a border with Idaho?", "answer": "Washington, Oregon, Nevada, Utah, Wyoming and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d06931a1c922dd1ac64ad", "question": "Who devised a method for classifying fingerprints?", "answer": "Francis Galton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e12", "question": "What two \"Brokeback Mountain\" actors have siblings who are also award-winning actors?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal and Randy Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eff", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Dudley Do-Right?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9ae8ebfabb9c85d8a980", "question": "The \"Althing\" is the national parliament of which country?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76e2deec85e375820b2db", "question": "Where did bungee jumping originate?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dc", "question": "What is a group of whales commonly called?", "answer": "Pod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c5", "question": "How many stars are in the Big Dipper?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfaa", "question": "James Hunt was disqualified after winning which Grand Prix?", "answer": "1976 British Grand Prix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c2a32b316f4693fb67a2", "question": "A task that has zero chance of success is known as what?", "answer": "Fool's Errand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339411", "question": "In the 2001 movie \"Dr. Dolittle 2\", what type of animal was Archie?", "answer": "Bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a213", "question": "What cartoon, from the Talkertoon series, marked the first appearance of Betty Boop?", "answer": "Dizzy Dishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df8ccf0cc2631d16a3c63", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd957ec223966ae8f88df", "question": "What movie villain was inspired, in part, by Katharine Hepburn?", "answer": "Hannibal Lector", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be580b85415ba52ed6f0ab7", "question": "What is the capital of Qatar?", "answer": "Doha", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6aac820565ad31a57c821", "question": "Who was the most decorated American soldier during World War II?", "answer": "Audie L Murphy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad62", "question": "What union was behind the \"Look for the Union Label\" advertising campaign?\"", "answer": "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b66f01dd7bf43be5e7dc", "question": "Queen Elizabeth technically owns thousands of what kind of animal?", "answer": "Swans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b447", "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick die?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5aab2e9358d116dab4aecb3f", "question": "Who played the inventor in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec88b4ec223966ae8f8822", "question": "The peripheral device that could be used to connect two Gameboys was called what?", "answer": "Game Link Cable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c4bf877e98cb977789a5", "question": "How many US states share a border with Quebec?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c5f3fbde8045e48466b3", "question": "A \"bloat\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- A group of hippos consist of 10 to 20 females, their young, and one male hippo.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c081", "question": "People with a lot of hair are said to suffer from what?", "answer": "Hypertrichosis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b5", "question": "Which French fashion designer created the conical bra for Madonna's \"Blond Ambition\" tour?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339323", "question": "What game does Beetlejuice play with Lydia to get her to guess his name?", "answer": "Charades", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c69", "question": "What literary character, in a novel by Cervantes, had a sidekick named Sancho Panza?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc1716de0eb824d4052df", "question": "What is the largest glacier in North America?", "answer": "Bering Glacier in Alaska holds the record as the largest glacier in North America.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a159", "question": "Which group starred in \"Magical Mystery Tour\"?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac4", "question": "What is the name for the number 1 followed by 100 zeros?", "answer": "Googol", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba29", "question": "What was the original name of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "Liberty Enlightening the World", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c8a50775fa611bce67e2", "question": "\"Veni, vidi, vici\" is a Latin phrase that translates to what?", "answer": "\"I came, I saw, I conquered\" -- Roman emperor Julius Caesar said this Latin phrase, as cited in Plutarch's \"Life of Caesar\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3d9", "question": "What is the world's second largest country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e5", "question": "What sport has its name abbreviated to BMX?", "answer": "Bicycle Moto-cross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f50", "question": "What network has aired \"Shark Week\" every summer since 1988?", "answer": "The Discovery Channel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11e", "question": "What famous animal character called \"Skull Island\" home?", "answer": "King Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339298", "question": "Which film sported the tag-line \"Just when you thought it was safe to go back in the water\"?", "answer": "Jaws 2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc3edec223966ae8f8882", "question": "Which player graced the cover of the videogame \"Madden NFL 17\"?", "answer": "Rob Gronkowski", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99b8221a8909e5c332d2c", "question": "When was the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" released?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b3", "question": "How many calories are stored in 1 pound of body fat?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a984", "question": "In what Caribbean country did steel drums originate?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea38baff048f679a45ab26", "question": "What is the average life cycle of a red blood cell?", "answer": "120 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2bf", "question": "What split up into Gondwanaland and Laurasia?", "answer": "Pangaea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899bed60d398dc9cf7a6a2", "question": "In the body, what is the CNS?", "answer": "Central Nervous System", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10b", "question": "By which name is Paul Francis Gadd better known?", "answer": "Gary Glitter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bbd0fb6c85e9e634ff59", "question": "What is the word \"laser\" short for?", "answer": "Light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a4", "question": "Venice's Grand Canal ends at what huge square, the city's only piazza?", "answer": "Piazza San Marco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70d", "question": "What is the name given to glittery strings hung on Christmas trees?", "answer": "Tinsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0db", "question": "What Tennessee university was the first college to field a men's basketball team, in 1893?", "answer": "Vanderbilt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5125fff04d658268c92cf", "question": "What group of American women displayed their loyalty following the passage of the Townshend Acts in 1767?", "answer": "The\u00a0Daughters of Liberty\u00a0used their traditional skills to develope substitutes for goods sold by the British.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339387", "question": "Who was the Castle Rock DJ in the movie \"Stand By Me\"?", "answer": "Bob Cormier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0ad2596a59cbdfbd37f", "question": "Who said, \"If a man is proud of his wealth, he should not be praised until it is known how he employs it\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a546", "question": "What is the capital of the US territory of Puerto Rico?", "answer": "San Juan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66bb2a5bfecdd737e0887", "question": "What was Merriam-Webster's word of the year for 2019?", "answer": "They", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc4", "question": "In 1939, Buck Ewing became the first Major League Baseball player from what position elected to the Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Catcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339039", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595641df803c1f1ebcc4a02b", "question": "What is the ball, or flat plate, that sits on top of a flag pole called?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca85", "question": "What culinary ingredient is French scientist Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s credited with inventing?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339593", "question": "What 2006 movie is sub-titled \"Hell on Heels\"?", "answer": "The Devil Wears Prada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69a", "question": "Why are capons castrated?", "answer": "To improve the quality of its flesh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c8877e98cb977789d7", "question": "Which Mediterranean city has an area nicknamed \"The White City\"?", "answer": "Tel Aviv", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51bc9ff04d658268c9310", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed6", "question": "Who fights crime alongside a German shepherd named Ace?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea467dff048f679a45aba3", "question": "What happens to your skin's blood vessels as you exercise?", "answer": "They widen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6ab0820565ad31a57c823", "question": "Who was the commander of German U-boats from 1939 to 1943?", "answer": "Admiral Karl Dointz (also spelled Doenitz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65de31f3c0ead6880d623", "question": "In 1472, Leonardo da Vinci became a member of which Florentine guild?", "answer": "Painter's Guild", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636c30967692ea851899a8", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the 2nd President of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a162c57f01ec323f849172f", "question": "Which was the first country to host 2 soccer World Cups?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedde376ce05a3942286dac", "question": "Who was originally supposed to direct the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a551d83e1c6f9840ba3190", "question": "What is a \"Pickelhaube\"?", "answer": "A spiked German helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78d", "question": "What are the three colors in the Jamaican flag?", "answer": "Black, green and yellow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e3", "question": "What \u201cStar Trek\u201d character had a name meaning \u201cfreedom\u201d in Swahili?", "answer": "Uhura", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9d", "question": "What movie marked the feature film debut for Rene Russo?", "answer": "Major League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b2904fda37788a9a1dbb", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer": "Frank McCourt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4a", "question": "According to poet Carl Sandburg, what \"creeps in on little cat feet\"?", "answer": "The fog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eeb", "question": "What movie's protagonist is named Lightning McQueen?", "answer": "Cars", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a9dc9bff04efae6d761", "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b276", "question": "How many soldiers are shown raising the flag over Iwo Jima in the famous photograph and statue?", "answer": "Six", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a44a", "question": "Which direction on a map do lines of latitude go?", "answer": "East to west", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e082fe83fe1f2a824b8e", "question": "Who won the first Nobel Prize for Medicine?", "answer": "Emil von Behring", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd5d2e347d002c297e4b8", "question": "The novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\" is the second book in which pentalogy?", "answer": "Leatherstocking Tales", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f62afe83fe1f2a824c1c", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab15dabaab681b0929217e", "question": "What was the world\u2019s first mass-produced car to feature an all-aluminium body?", "answer": "Honda NSX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c040", "question": "What is a group of Oxen called?", "answer": "Yoke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33c", "question": "Lock, Shock and Barrel were characters in which Halloween film?", "answer": "The Nightmare Before Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3106ce05a3942286f1d", "question": "Who played the role of Hannibal Lector in the film \"Manhunter\"?", "answer": "Brian Cox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45d", "question": "A spider typically has eight legs and eight what?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe530031bf59ab7d2e38118", "question": "How many states does the Hoover Dam power?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27c", "question": "Who had a record song in 1963 with their cover of \"Sweets for My Sweet\"?\u00a0", "answer": "The Searchers\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29d", "question": "Who starred as the male lead in the Alfred Hitchcock film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c7130775fa611bce67d5", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" -- It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e36", "question": "What game show host took his stage name from the college in his West Virginia hometown?", "answer": "Peter Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47119f8e329de4f877898", "question": "How many standard bottles of wine are there in a Nebuchadnezzar?", "answer": "20 Bottles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae8", "question": "Twin brothers Ross and Norris McWhirter are best known for creating what reference book?", "answer": "Guinness Book of World Records", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc2", "question": "What disease is Mitch Albom's professor dying of in his best-seller \"Tuesday with Morrie\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig's disease", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339add", "question": "What man, later a news anchor, hosted the 1954 CBS quiz show called \"It's News to Me\"?", "answer": "Walter Cronkite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83d", "question": "How high is the crossbar on a football goal post?", "answer": "10 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1ac7baab681b09292196", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea45faff048f679a45ab9d", "question": "How much does a lobster increase in size while molting?", "answer": "25%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a1b620565ad31a57c7a5", "question": "What was the first US state to have two female senators at the same time?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3bec44f0f6af5b066629", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"The Grinder\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afad", "question": "Off of which European coastline was the \"Battle of Trafalgar\" fought?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f6", "question": "What Beatles song begins with the opening fanfare from the French national anthem?", "answer": "All You Need is Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3a", "question": "How many players are there in a standard ultimate frisbee team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f5", "question": "Which continent is home to the Tasmanian Devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911b", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish the novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "1895", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded2ebea2747c8aff16d43", "question": "What is a device to stem the flow of blood called?", "answer": "A tourniquet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601219cf63c99d48cd169afb", "question": "What is someone who shoes horses?", "answer": "A farrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab87", "question": "What country is Phnom Penh the capital of?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c74", "question": "Rupert Giles was the librarian-mentor on what popular TV show?", "answer": "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c2", "question": "What is Marilyn Monroe's real name?", "answer": "Norma Jeane Mortenson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2d", "question": "What Greek god, killed by a wild boar, inspired Percy Shelley's elegy for his friend Keats?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc30dec223966ae8f887a", "question": "Cricket stars Clyde Walcott, Everton Weekes and Frank Worrell were all born in which city within 18 months of each other?", "answer": "Bridgetown, Barbados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab94c586faa38a764be510", "question": "Who bought the rights to manufacture the Isetta in the 1950\u2019s from the Italian company Iso?", "answer": "BMW", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c9", "question": "Until 1790, what was known as Jenkins Hill?", "answer": "Capitol Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19b", "question": "Belle, Spike, Olaf, Marbles, and Andy are siblings of which Peanuts character?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b248", "question": "What world leader began his plan to take power after the 1989 Caracazo riots?", "answer": "Hugo Chavez", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6659fa5bfecdd737e0861", "question": "Who were the first people to use currency?", "answer": "Lydians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78c", "question": "Approximately how long is the Congo River?", "answer": "2,900 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae12", "question": "In which decade did Mao Zedong come to power in China?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f492aaf848b908361b87a", "question": "Which legume can be processed to make dynamite?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd99", "question": "How many points is the red inner circle on a dartboard bull's-eye worth?", "answer": "Fifty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c8", "question": "What instrument was played by jazz musician Glenn Miller?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cda", "question": "What British statesman wrote \"A History of the English-Speaking People\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c181", "question": "The skin of which animal is used to make the finest grade Morocco Leather?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}]